<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Adrenalinemie</title><link>https://adrenalinemie.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Settling down in Cambridge</title><link>https://adrenalinemie.github.io/blog/Settling_down_in_Cambridge.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;French translation at the bottom of the page / Traduction Française en bas de&amp;nbsp;page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crossing the Channel and settling in&amp;nbsp;Cambridge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="http://i.imgur.com/Q0W5LzE.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been five months since we moved to Cambridge. Five intense and exciting months, even though everything has not always been easy. Indeed, living far from our families and friends sometimes makes us feel gloomy and sometimes homesick. Fortunately, Cambridge is a very welcoming city with really friendly&amp;nbsp;people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first arrived in Cambridge by train loaded to the hilt, on 24th April, and the following day, Adrien started his new job! Crossing Paris in the Subway with 2 luggages each and a dismantled bike was quite a challenge, but we painstakingly handled&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/6j7qN"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/6j7qN"&gt;The Eurostar with a ton of luggages and a bike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first fifteen days were quite weird and a bit shaky because we were staying in an &lt;em&gt;AirBnb&lt;/em&gt; place which was not really great. Fortunately, it was only&amp;nbsp;temporary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to checking out houses to let, but quickly realised that we could not afford the kind of property we wanted. We decided to lower our requirements, and I started to look for a flat. We quickly found a really good option: renting an apartment in an “apart hotel” building. The advantage is that the price includes everything so you don’t need to bother about things like the Internet, the electricity/services … Furthermore, it’s all furnished, which is an important point when you have almost no furniture (we sold most of ours when we left Nantes)! Our flat is conveniently located between the train station and the city centre, so we can go almost everywhere on foot! Adrien can commute easily to work by bicycle or free bus (one of the perks of his&amp;nbsp;job!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="http://i.imgur.com/eq4gWrM.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks after our first journey, we brought most of our stuff from France, thanks to the (fully-packed) Adrien’s parents’ Kangoo; it was a great adventure with our little Saya who was so adorable during the long journey, despite having a high fever due to an infection she got after an unfortunate fight with another&amp;nbsp;cat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/pzwZB"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/pzwZB"&gt;To Albion in a Kangoo packed to bursting point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few words from&amp;nbsp;Adrien…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far so good … My colleagues were extremely welcoming and we often go bouldering together in Cambridge, and this usually ends in a pub! My new job is interesting and challenging because it’s quite a new field for me, but I’m willing to take advantage of the opportunity. After all, 3 years is a short amount of time. The institute is amazing and there is no shortage of money &lt;a href="https://www.ebi.ac.uk/about"&gt;European Bioinformatic Institute&lt;/a&gt;. Apart from work, I am a member of a &lt;a href="http://makespace.org/"&gt;Makespace&lt;/a&gt; where I’ve been making things, such as furniture and a new bike trailer. Next, I will try to learn new things about electronics and wood&amp;nbsp;working.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few words from&amp;nbsp;Melanie…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m currently unemployed as I had to get a high grade in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt; exam (= Academic English exam test) before applying for a licence to practise, which obviously makes sense for a psychiatrist! Once I get this licence, I will be able to apply for a job. But, I am still  hyperactive, so I do many things, and I am never bored! I’ve been studying hard for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt; exam. When I arrived in England, I attended special English classes for 5 weeks, but now I did so by myself. I have met some very welcoming and charming people who are helping me improve: Maggie, a retired English teacher who is actually really active (I suspect that she is more hyperactive than I am!), and organizes, among other things, free classes for foreign people, and Cathy with whom I practice English-French conversation exchange. There is also the reading group every Wednesday at the library. Secondly, I’m working twice a week (Tuesday and Sunday) in a charity shop (Cancer Research). Charity shops are everywhere in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; and for everything. I really enjoy doing this. I have learnt how to sort clothes, put on the tickets (with a sort of gun!), and use the till, which I prefer! But there’s also the gym, running club, sewing&amp;#8230; However, I am really eager to get back to psychiatry. There is hope for me as I just got the required grade in my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt; exam, and I met a consultant psychiatrist who is happy to supervise me for a clinical attachment, a sort of training in which I&amp;#8217;m shadowing her. It all takes much more time than I expected, but if everything goes as planned I will be allowed to work before the end of the&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F#####g&amp;nbsp;Brexit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we should mention the Brexit which happened about 2 months after our arrival. Of course we were extremely surprised and disappointed. We even had second thoughts about our stay in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing has changed in Cambridge where the population voted massively in favour of remaining in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt;. Undoubtedly, it was a vote mainly against the government and immigration. There is a lot to say more about this, but it’s not really a topic for our blog, even though it is likely to have an effect on our future life in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; when Brexit is enacted. We are just waiting for 2017 and will see how the negotiations&amp;nbsp;go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, except this unexpected event, I should say that our life in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; had got off to a good start and we are really enjoying the multicultural and extremely culturally rich city, even though we obviously miss our French friends and family a&amp;nbsp;lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ET&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8230; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QUE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DIEU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PROTEGE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LA&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;REINE&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;^^&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La traversée de la manche et l&amp;#8217;installation à&amp;nbsp;Cambridge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="http://i.imgur.com/Q0W5LzE.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cela fait cinq mois que nous avons déménagé à Cambridge. Cinq intenses et excitants mois, même si tout n’a pas été facile tous les jours. En effet, étant loin de nos familles et amis, nous nous sentons parfois maussades et le mal du pays nous gagne. Heureusement, Cambridge est une ville très accueillante avec des gens vraiment&amp;nbsp;sympathiques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous sommes arrivés à Cambridge, chargés comme des mules, le 24 Avril, et le jour suivant, Adrien commençait son nouveau travail! La traversée de Paris avec 2 gros bagages chacun et un velo demonté n&amp;#8217;a pas été une sinécure mais on s&amp;#8217;en est sortis, non sans&amp;nbsp;peine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/6j7qN"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/6j7qN"&gt;The Eurostar with a ton of luggages and a bike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nos 15 premiers jours ont été un peu étranges et instables car nous logions dans un AirBnb qui n’était pas terrible. Heureusement, c’était seulement&amp;nbsp;temporaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J’ai commencé à chercher une maison à louer, mais je me suis vite rendue compte que nous ne pourrions pas nous permettre le type de propriété que nous envisagions. Nous avons donc décidé de revoir nos exigences à la baisse, et j’ai commencé à regarder les appartements. Nous avons alors rapidement trouvé une bonne alternative: louer un appartement dans un “appart hotel”. Un des avantages est que c’est “tout inclus” et donc nous n’avons pas eu à nous soucier des choses comme l’abonnement à internet, l’électricité… De plus, c’est entièrement meublé, ce qui est important quand on a presque pas de meubles (nous avons vendu la plupart de nos meubles en quittant Nantes)! Notre appartement est très bien situé entre la gare et le centre ville, on peut donc aller presque partout à pied! Adrien peut facilement aller à son travail à vélo ou avec le bus gratuit (un des avantages de son&amp;nbsp;travail!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="http://i.imgur.com/eq4gWrM.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous avons ensuite apporté nos affaires de France grâce au Kangoo des parents d’Adrien (complètement plein à craquer). Ça a été une véritable aventure avec notre petite Saya qui a vraiment été adorable durant ce long voyage, malgré sa fièvre due à l&amp;#8217;infection d’une grosse plaie qu&amp;#8217;elle a eue après une baston avec un autre&amp;nbsp;chat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/pzwZB"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/pzwZB"&gt;To Albion in a Kangoo packed to bursting point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quelques mot&amp;nbsp;d’Adrien…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pour le moment tout va pour le mieux. Mes collègues ont été très accueillants et nous allons régulièrement grimper ensemble dans une salle de bloc à Cambridge. Ça termine généralement au Pub. Mon nouveau boulot est captivant mais représente également un défi, car le domaine de recherche est relativement nouveau pour moi. En tout cas c&amp;#8217;est une belle opportunité dont je vais profiter au maximum dans les 3 ans impartis. L&amp;#8217;institut est vraiment cool et ce ne sont pas les moyens financiers qui manquent &lt;a href="https://www.ebi.ac.uk/about"&gt;European Bioinformatic Institute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. A coté du travail, je me suis inscrit dans le falblab de Cambridge (&lt;a href="http://makespace.org/"&gt;Makespace&lt;/a&gt;) où je fabrique des choses (meubles, nouvelle remorque pour mon vélo&amp;#8230;). Je vais aussi essayer d&amp;#8217;apprendre un peu l’électronique et le travail du&amp;nbsp;bois.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quelques mots de&amp;nbsp;Mélanie…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actuellement, je n’ai pas de travail car j&amp;#8217;ai dû passer un examen académique d’anglais (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt;) avant de faire ma demande de licence pour exercer, ce qui bien sûr prend son sens pour une psychiatre! Une fois la licence en poche, je vais pouvoir postuler pour un travail. Mais je suis toujours aussi active, donc je fais beaucoup de choses et je ne m’ennuie vraiment pas! J’ai travaillé dur mon mon examen d’anglais. Quand je suis arrivée en Angleterre, j’ai pris 5 semaines de cours, puis j’ai continué à étudié par moi-même. J’ai rencontré des personnes très accueillantes et charmantes: Maggie, une professeur d’anglais à la retraite qui est en fait très active (je suspecte qu’elle soit plus hyperactive que je ne le suis!), et organise, entre autre, des cours gratuits pour les étrangers, et Cathy avec qui je fais régulièrement un échange de conversation anglais-français. Il y a aussi le groupe de lecture tous les mercredis à la bibliothèque. De plus, je travaille deux fois par semaine (mardi et dimanche) dans un magasin de charité (pour la recherche contre le cancer). Les magasins de charité sont partout dans le Royaume-Uni, et pour tout. J’apprécie vraiment cela. J’ai appris comment trier les habits, étiquetter (avec une sorte de pistolet!) et utiliser la caisse enregistreuse, ce que je préfère! Mais il y a aussi la gym, le club de course, la couture… Cependant, j’ai vraiment hâte de revenir vers la psychiatrie. J’ai de l’espoir car je viens de réussir mon examen d’anglais avec le score requis, et j’ai rencontré une psychiatre qui accepte de me superviser pour un stage d’observation, que je viens de commencer. Cela prend plus de temps que je ne l’imaginais, mais j’espère pouvoir travailler avant la fin de&amp;nbsp;l’année.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pu%@# de&amp;nbsp;Brexit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peut-être devrions-nous parler du Brexit qui est survenu 2 mois après notre arrivée. Bien sûr, nous avons été extrêmement surpris et déçus. Nous avons même remis en question notre installation au Royaume-Uni. Rien n’a changé à Cambridge où la population a massivement voté pro-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UE&lt;/span&gt;. Il s’agit, sans aucun doute, d’un vote principalement contre le gouvernement en place et l’immigration. Il y aurait beaucoup à dire à ce propos, mais ce n’est pas vraiment le sujet de notre blog, même si notre future vie ici va très probablement être impactée quand le Brexit sera acté. Nous attendons juste 2017 pour voir comment vont se passer les&amp;nbsp;négociations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bref, à part cette événement inattendu, je dois dire que notre vie au Royaume-Uni a pris un bon départ et que nous sommes très satisfaits de cette ville multiculturelle et extrêmement riche au niveau culturel, même si nous amis français et notre famille nous manquent&amp;nbsp;beaucoup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And&amp;#8230; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GOD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAVE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;THE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QUEEN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;^^&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrien</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:adrenalinemie.github.io,2016-10-05:blog/Settling_down_in_Cambridge.html</guid></item><item><title>Welcome to Albion</title><link>https://adrenalinemie.github.io/blog/Welcome-to-Albion.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Across the white cliffs of&amp;nbsp;Albion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we&amp;nbsp;are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We settled in Cambridge in East-Anglia and we have been living there for nearly 5 months. Cambridge is a rather peculiar city, built around a massive 700 years old University, which spread in virtually all the city centre. The city is built along the river Cam, crossed by numerous bridges&amp;nbsp;(Cam-Bridge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a heavily international place, where Art, History, Literature and Science students and teachers from all around the world mingle and share knowledge, and maybe&amp;nbsp;more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we tell you more, enjoy this overview of our new and beautiful&amp;nbsp;city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/4jsLJ"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/4jsLJ"&gt;Cambridge Top of the Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come very soon&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Par delà les blanches falaises&amp;nbsp;d&amp;#8217;Albion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Çà y est nous y&amp;nbsp;sommes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous nous sommes installés a Cambridge en East-Anglia (Sud Est de l’Angleterre), il y a maintenant presque 5 mois. Cambridge est une ville assez particulière, construite autours d&amp;#8217;une gigantesque université vieille de plus de 700 ans, qui englobe quasiment tout le centre ville. La ville est construite de part et d’autre de la rivière Cam traversée par de nombreux ponts&amp;nbsp;(Cam-Bridge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’est un lieu très international, où se mélangent les étudiants et professeurs d’Art, d’Histoire, de Littérature, et de Science venant des quatre coins du globe pour partager des connaissances, et plus si&amp;nbsp;affinité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans l’attente de vous en dévoiler un petit peu plus, voici un petit aperçu de notre nouvelle et jolie&amp;nbsp;ville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/4jsLJ"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/4jsLJ"&gt;Cambridge Top of the Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suite à venir très bientôt&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrien</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:adrenalinemie.github.io,2016-09-23:blog/Welcome-to-Albion.html</guid></item></channel></rss>