<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Adrenalinemie</title><link>https://adrenalinemie.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Welcome to Albion</title><link>https://adrenalinemie.github.io/blog/Welcome-to-Albion.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Across the white cliffs of&amp;nbsp;Albion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we&amp;nbsp;are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We settled in Cambridge in East-Anglia and we have been living there for nearly 5 months. Cambridge is a rather peculiar city, built around a massive 700 years old University, which spread in virtually all the city centre. The city is built along the river Cam, crossed by numerous bridges&amp;nbsp;(Cam-Bridge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a heavily international place, where Art, History, Literature and Science students and teachers from all around the world mingle and share knowledge, and maybe&amp;nbsp;more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we tell you more, enjoy this overview of our new and beautiful&amp;nbsp;city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/4jsLJ"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/4jsLJ"&gt;Cambridge Top of the Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come very soon&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Par delà les blanches falaises&amp;nbsp;d&amp;#8217;Albion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Çà y est nous y&amp;nbsp;sommes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous nous sommes installés a Cambridge en East-Anglia (Sud Est de l’Angleterre), il y a maintenant presque 5 mois. Cambridge est une ville assez particulière, construite autours d&amp;#8217;une gigantesque université vieille de plus de 700 ans, qui englobe quasiment tout le centre ville. La ville est construite de part et d’autre de la rivière Cam traversée par de nombreux ponts&amp;nbsp;(Cam-Bridge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’est un lieu très international, où se mélangent les étudiants et professeurs d’Art, d’Histoire, de Littérature, et de Science venant des quatre coins du globe pour partager des connaissances, et plus si&amp;nbsp;affinité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans l’attente de vous en dévoiler un petit peu plus, voici un petit aperçu de notre nouvelle et jolie&amp;nbsp;ville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/4jsLJ"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/4jsLJ"&gt;Cambridge Top of the Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suite à venir très bientôt&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Adrien</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:adrenalinemie.github.io,2016-09-23:blog/Welcome-to-Albion.html</guid></item></channel></rss>