<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Adrenalinemie</title><link href="https://adrenalinemie.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://adrenalinemie.github.io/feeds/melanie.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://adrenalinemie.github.io/</id><updated>2016-10-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Settling down in Cambridge</title><link href="https://adrenalinemie.github.io/blog/Settling_down_in_Cambridge.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Adrien</name></author><id>tag:adrenalinemie.github.io,2016-10-05:blog/Settling_down_in_Cambridge.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been five months since we moved to Cambridge. Five intense and exciting months, even though everything has not always been easy. Indeed, living far from our families and friends sometimes makes us feel gloomy and sometimes homesick. Fortunately, Cambridge is a very welcoming city with really friendly&amp;nbsp;people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first arrived in Cambridge by train loaded to the hilt, on 24th April, and the following day, Adrien started his new job! Crossing Paris in the Subway with 2 luggages each and a dismantled bike was had been quite a&amp;nbsp;challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/6j7qN"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/6j7qN"&gt;The Eurostar with a ton of luggages and a bike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first fifteen days were quite weird and a bit shaky because we were staying in an &lt;em&gt;AirBnb&lt;/em&gt; place which was not really great. Fortunately, it was only&amp;nbsp;temporary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to checking out houses to let, but quickly realised that we could not afford the kind of property we wanted. We decided to lower our requirements, and I started to look for a flat. We quickly found a really good option: renting an apartment in an “apart hotel” building. The advantage is that the price includes everything so you don’t need to bother about things like the Internet, the electricity/services … Furthermore, it’s all furnished, which is an important point when you have almost no furniture (we sold most of ours furniture when we left&amp;nbsp;Nantes)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our flat is conveniently located between the train station and the city centre, so we can go almost everywhere on foot! Adrien can commute easily to work by bicycle or free bus (one of the perks of his&amp;nbsp;job!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks after our first journey, we brought most of our stuff from France, thanks to the (fully-packed) Adrien’s parents’ Kangoo; it was a great adventure with our little Saya who was so adorable during the long journey, despite having a high fever due to an infection she got after an unfortunate fight with another&amp;nbsp;cat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/pzwZB"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/pzwZB"&gt;To Albion in a Kangoo packed to bursting point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few words from&amp;nbsp;Adrien…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far so good … My colleagues were extremely welcoming and we often go bouldering in Cambridge, and this usually ends in a pub! My new job is interesting and challenging because it’s a quite a new field for me, but I’m willing to take advantage of the opportunity. After all, 3 years is a short amount of time. Apart from work, I am a member of a “Makespace” group where I’ve been making things, such as furniture and a new bike trailer. Next, I will try to learn new things about electronics and wood&amp;nbsp;working.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few words from&amp;nbsp;Melanie…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m currently unemployed as I have to get a high grade at the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt; exam (= Academic English exam test) before applying for a licence to practise, which obviously makes sense for a psychiatrist! Once I get this licence, I will be able to apply for a job. But, I am still  hyperactive, so I do many things, and I am never bored! I’ve been studying hard for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt; exam. When I arrived in England, I attended special English classes for 5 weeks, but now I’m doing so by myself. I have met some very welcoming and charming people who are helping me improve: Maggie, a retired English teacher who is actually really active (I suspect that she is more hyperactive than I am!), and organizes, among other things, free classes for foreign people, and Cathy with whom I practice English-French conversation exchange. There is also the reading group every Wednesday at the library. Secondly, I’m working twice a week (Tuesday and Sunday) in a charity shop (Cancer Research). Charity shops are everywhere in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; and for everything. I really enjoy doing this. I have learnt how to sort clothes, put on the tickets (with a sort of gun!), and use the till, which I prefer! But there’s also the gym, running club, sewing&amp;#8230; However, I am really eager to get back to psychiatry. There is hope for me as I just got the required grade in my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IELTS&lt;/span&gt; exam, and I met a consultant psychiatrist who is happy to supervise me for a clinical attachment, a sort of training in which I will shadow her. It all takes much more time than I expected, but if everything goes as planned I will be allowed to work before the end of the&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we should mention the Brexit which happened about 2 months after our arrival. Of course we were extremely surprised and disappointed. We even had second thoughts about our stay in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing has changed in Cambridge where the population voted massively in favour of remaining in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt;. Undoubtedly, it was a vote mainly against the government and immigration. There is a lot to say more about this, but it’s not really a topic for our blog, even though it is likely to have an effect on our future life in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; when Brexit is enacted. We are just waiting for 2017 and will see how the negotiations&amp;nbsp;go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, except this unexpected event, I should say that our life in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; had got off to a good start and we are really enjoying the multicultural and extremely culturally rich city, even though we obviously miss our French friends and family a&amp;nbsp;lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FRENCH&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;COMING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Welcome to Albion</title><link href="https://adrenalinemie.github.io/blog/Welcome-to-Albion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Adrien</name></author><id>tag:adrenalinemie.github.io,2016-09-23:blog/Welcome-to-Albion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Across the white cliffs of&amp;nbsp;Albion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we&amp;nbsp;are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We settled in Cambridge in East-Anglia and we have been living there for nearly 5 months. Cambridge is a rather peculiar city, built around a massive 700 years old University, which spread in virtually all the city centre. The city is built along the river Cam, crossed by numerous bridges&amp;nbsp;(Cam-Bridge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a heavily international place, where Art, History, Literature and Science students and teachers from all around the world mingle and share knowledge, and maybe&amp;nbsp;more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we tell you more, enjoy this overview of our new and beautiful&amp;nbsp;city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/4jsLJ"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/4jsLJ"&gt;Cambridge Top of the Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come very soon&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Par delà les blanches falaises&amp;nbsp;d&amp;#8217;Albion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Çà y est nous y&amp;nbsp;sommes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous nous sommes installés a Cambridge en East-Anglia (Sud Est de l’Angleterre), il y a maintenant presque 5 mois. Cambridge est une ville assez particulière, construite autours d&amp;#8217;une gigantesque université vieille de plus de 700 ans, qui englobe quasiment tout le centre ville. La ville est construite de part et d’autre de la rivière Cam traversée par de nombreux ponts&amp;nbsp;(Cam-Bridge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’est un lieu très international, où se mélangent les étudiants et professeurs d’Art, d’Histoire, de Littérature, et de Science venant des quatre coins du globe pour partager des connaissances, et plus si&amp;nbsp;affinité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans l’attente de vous en dévoiler un petit peu plus, voici un petit aperçu de notre nouvelle et jolie&amp;nbsp;ville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/4jsLJ"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/4jsLJ"&gt;Cambridge Top of the Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suite à venir très bientôt&amp;nbsp;!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>